Big O notation.
Is a mathematical notation that describes the limiting behavior of a function when the argument tends
to was a particular value or infinity in computer science.
Bingo notation is used to classify algorithms according to how they're run.
Time or space requirements grow at the input size grows big o notation characterizes functions according
to their growth rates so that different functions with the same growth rate may be representing using
the same notation the letter O used because the growth rate of the function is also referred to us or
two as an order of a function.
So all is the order of function.
'kay.
No, a description of your function in terms of connotation usually only provides an upper bound on
their growth rate of a function.
So function, if we have a function, we have lower bound and upper bound.
Also, we have if we have an algorithm, we have the lower bound and the upper bound, which we have.
Take an example in the previous video that we have an algorithm that can be executed by one second and
another algorithm that do the same result and the same computation in 10 seconds.
So the lower bound is one second in this case, and the upper bound is 10 seconds in this case.
So we are going to and we are interested in understanding and studying this upper bound.
We don't care about the lower bound.
So in computer engineering, we don't care about that.
The best case we need the worst case to make it to lower its order, to make it better and better.
So the upper bound is donated by oh so associated with big o notation are several related notation using
the symbol like omega set and then much more to describe other kinds of bound synthetic growth.
Right?
OK.
So.
Let's assume.
This notation, it gives the tight upper bound of a given function.
Generally, it is presented as f of an equal duo of G of N.
This means at larger values of and the upper bound of F and is g of a.
We are not going to make a deep representation in mathematics, but I'm just telling you that that this
big O notation is the highest order in the in the function.
OK.
So if you have and power four plus and two power three plus and power two, we took A. Power four as
it's sort of presenting value.
Don't worry.
And the next videos, we are going to make an example about exercises, about big o notation.
And we will clarify all of these things.
I need from you to to take a quick look about this lower bound average time and upper bound and these
algorithm.
So we start by, oh, two out of one.
And oh look n.
So this is the green of one.
This is that a greenish low look and this is a yellow of A..
So see, guys, we are moving from that linear oh and look and n two and log and you see the difference
here and we start by.
Excellent.
This is of one.
Good luck.
MN fair is of and these are algorithms are good.
While and look and as bad and the horrible things that we are that may we may encounter is of and powerless
and square or of truth, power and and and factory.
Your mission and you are asked to make the horrible notations and horrible algorithms like a good and
fair and maybe excellent algorithm, so your mission is to make these.
Algorithms.
Do these good algorithms?
This is the data structure and algorithm target and goal.
So this is your mission.
You need to reduce the oh the oh notation.
The order, the order of the function of the algorithm do the least thing that you may are you try to
make it lower.
And so we started from Biggert end and we need to decrease it to lower.